Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 9 Month(s)

Notice Period: 2 Months

Highest Degree:

SHIVAM AGARWAL () Featured

Lead Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Database Development, Solution Architecture, Technical Management, Client Management, Selenium, Linux, SQL, Java



Current Designation: Lead Engineer

Current Company: Samsung Research Institute Bangalore

(SRIB)

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Database Development, Powercenter, Linux, SQL, Java, JUnit

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

I have a total experience of 4+ years.

Worked as ETL developer for 2 years using technologies like: Informatica powercenter, SQL, VBA.

Worked as Software developer for 2+ years using technologies like JAVA, Unix, Junit, Robot Framework

Work Experience

Samsung Research Institute Bangalore (SRIB) as Lead Engineer Jan 2020 to Till Date

-Working in Telecom Domain Element Management system (EMS). Efficiently providing TAC3 support to 4G network for Jio, SKT, YTL, 3UK, AT&T etc. -Development and Enhancement done on EMS according to the requirements of clients. - Written Junit and Selenium code for Code and UI testing

Cognizant Technologies Solutions as Associate

Feb 2016 to Jan 2020

Java, Informatica, SQL, VBA developer

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computer Science) from Jaypee University of Engineering and Technology, guna in 2015

PG: in 0

IT Skills

| Skill Name | Version | Last Used | Experience | |
|--------------------------|---------|-----------|----------------------|--|
| VB Macro, SQL, JAVA | | 2019 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| Informatica Power Centre | | 2019 | 3 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |
| JAVA | | 2019 | 4 Year(s) 4 Month(s) | |
| Selenium testing | | 2020 | 1 Year(s) 0 Month(s) | |

Languages Known

| Language | Proficiency | Read | Write | Speak |
|----------|-------------|------|-------|-------|
| Hindi | Expert | | | |
| English | Expert | | | |

Projects

Project Title: Element management system-SRIB

Client: Multiple Industries

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Jan 2020 - Till Date Project Location: Bangalore** Onsite / Offsite: Offsite Team Size: 24 Role: Sr. Programmer

Skill Used: Java, JUnit, Selenium Testing, Linux Server Role Description: Enhancement and Bug fixes in the EMS.

Written JUnit for code testing. written Selenium for UI testing.

Project Details: development, enhancements and bug fixes of an Element Management System (EMS). this EMS

provides 5G services to different clients like jio, KDDI, SKT, KT, LGU+.

Project Title: Data Integration Workbench-COGNIZANT

Client: multiple clients -internal tool Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Feb 2017 - Jan 2020 Project Location: Bangalore Onsite / Offsite: Onsite Role: Programmer Team Size: 6

Skill Used: Java , SQL, informatica, XML, VBA, Alteryx

Role Description: making of an smart excel sheet using VBA, Developed Java functions to convert that sheet into

XML, Another Java Utility converts XML to Excel.

Developed Java Utility to convert java, JSONObjects to XML file.

Project Details: automation of ETL tools -informatica and data stage using VBA, Java, XML

Project Title: VMWARE Tableau Desktop- COGNIZANT

Client: VMware Inc

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Feb 2017 - Feb 2018** Onsite / Offsite: Offsite **Project Location: Bangalore**

Team Size: 3 Role: Other

Skill Used: Tableau, SQL

Project Details: VMWARE HANA Migration focused on migrating all business reports from Green Plum Database to HANA Database. Development and enhancement of dashboard based on pre, post sales and the order management of thr data and the performance of the employees.

Performance testing of previously built reports and optimisations.

Worked with Business users to understand the user requirements, layout and look and feel of the application to be developed

Data blending between SAP HANA and already published data sources and generated interactive dashboards.

Involved in creating Hierarchies, Calculated fields, Table calculations, Quick filters, Actions, Sets, Parameters, Sorting, Data blending and Formatting of reports and dashboards.

Created ad-hoc reports to users in Tableau by connecting various data sources.

Generated dashboards with Quick filters, Parameters and Sets to handle views more efficiently.

Published Workbooks by creating user filters so that only appropriate team can

Project Title: AIG - Informatica power center-COGNIZANT

Client: AIG

Nature of Employment: Full Time **Duration: Feb 2016 - Feb 2017 Project Location: Kolkata** Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Role: Programmer Team Size: 30

Skill Used: Informatica Power Center, , SQL,

Role Description: Development, enhancement and tuning of different types of mappings.

Project Details: Developed mappings for Client-AIG(American International Group) that perform Extraction, Transformation and load of source data into Derived Masters schema using various power centre transformations like Source Qualifier, Aggregator, Filter, Router, Sequence Generator, lookup, Rank, Joiner, Expression, Stored

Procedure, SQL, and update strategy to meet business logic in the mappings

Tuning of Informatica mappings and sessions for optimum performance.

Assisted the other ETL developers in solving complex scenarios and coordinated with source systems owners with day-to-day ETL progress monitoring.

Reusable transformations and Mapplets are built wherever reusability is needed

Used Oracle to write SQL queries that create/alter/delete tables and to extract the necessary data.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No **Employment Status: Full time**